

□ PHONENUMBER | ■ EMAILADDRESS | 🏕 jaewonchung.me | 🖸 jaywonchung | 🛅 jae-won-chung-cs

Summary .

I am a third year PhD candidate in CSE at the University of Michigan, working with <u>Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury</u>. I build efficient software systems for deep learning, with a recent focus on the efficient management of not only time, but also energy. I lead the <u>ML Energy initiative</u>.

Education

University of Michigan

PH.D. CANDIDATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

University of Michigan

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Seoul National University

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

- GPA: 4.04/4.3 (overall) 4.15/4.3 (major), Summa Cum Laude
- · Period includes two years of military service.

Publications

- Perseus: Removing Energy Bloat from Large Model Training, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Yile Gu, Insu Jang, Luoxi Meng, Nikhil Bansal, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Preprint, 2023
- Chasing Low-Carbon Electricity for Practical and Sustainable DNN Training, Zhenning Yang, Luoxi Meng, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Mosharaf Chowdhury, ICLR Workshop: Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning, 2023
- Zeus: Understanding and Optimizing GPU Energy Consumption of DNN Training, Jie You*, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>*, Mosharaf Chowdhury,
 Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2023 (Acceptance rate = 18.38%)
- ShadowTutor: Distributed Partial Distillation for Mobile Video DNN Inference, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Jae-Yun Kim, Soo-Mook Moon, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP), 2020 (Acceptance rate = 28.99%)
- * Equal contribution

Experience

Energy-Efficient Systems for Machine Learning

SymbioticLab, UMich

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Sep 2021 - Apr 2023

Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2015 - Aug 2021

Sep 2021 - present

Advisor: Mosharaf Chowdhury

- Sep 2022 Present
- <u>Zeus</u>: Discovered the trade-off between DNN training time and energy. Designed a Multi-Armed Bandit solution for time-energy optimization.
 <u>Perseus</u>: A system for energy-efficient large model training. Cuts up to 30% energy without slowdown.
- ML.ENERGY Leaderboard & Colosseum: The first systematic benchmark and interactive comparison service for LLM energy consumption.

Software Systems for Machine Learning

Software Platform Lab, SNU

Advisor: Byung-Gon Chun

Apr 2020 - Jun 2022

• Crane: A GPU cluster manager for AutoML workloads. Built a Kubernetes backend that scaled to 288 GPUs. Contributed core features such as automatic bootstrapping on Docker Swarm and Kubernetes and log streaming through the EFK (Elasticsearch - Fluent Bit - Kibana) stack.

Online Model Specialization for Edge Video DNN Inference

Virtual Machine and Optimization Lab, SNU

ADVISOR: SOO-MOOK MOON

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

• ShadowTutor: Knowledge distillation from the server to the edge device reduced network data transfer by 95% and increased throughput by 3x.

Few-Shot Learning with Meta-Learning

Computer Vision Lab, SNU

ADVISOR: KYOUNG MU LEE

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

Designed improved meta-initialization methods for Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) with neural memory modules and convex programs.

Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping with Deep Learning

Lab of Imaging Science and Technology, SNU

ADVISOR: JONGHO LEE

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Designed and implemented a full deep learning pipeline for QSM, a vision task for medical diagnostics with 3D MRI field data, including preprocessing (background removal, phase unwrapping, and patch slicing), augmentation (adding fake calcifications) and modeling (<u>CAD-QSMNet</u>).

March 8, 2024 Jae-Won Chung

Open Source Projects _____

- BERT4Rec-VAE-Pytorch (☆318 ₺ 78), Implementation of BERT4Rec and Netflix VAE recommendation models. PyTorch.
- **Reason** (☆184 🎖 4), A shell for research papers. Rust.
- Zeus (☆117 🎖 16), An energy optimization framework for DNN training. Python and C++.
- Pegasus (☆27 ₺ 3), An SSH command runner with a focus on simplicity. Rust.

Number of stars and forks are as of March 8th, 2024.

Honors & Awards _____

Nov 2022 Carbon Hack '22 Second Best Solution, <u>Carbon-Aware DNN Training with Zeus</u> , \$25,000	Green Software Foundation
Jul 2021 Kwanjeong Overseas Scholarship, \$100,000 over four years	Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

Mar 2019 **Kwanjeong Undergraduate Scholarship**, \$20,000 over two years

Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

Grants & Funding _____

Jan 2024 Research grant , \$20,000 for the development of the ML.ENERGY Initiative	Salesforce
Jan 2024 Mozilla Technology Fund 2024, \$50,000 for the development of the Zeus project	Mozilla

Invited Talks _____

Oct 2023 Energy-Efficient Software Systems for Machine Learning	Seoul National University
Oct 2023 Energy-Efficient Deep Learning with PyTorch and Zeus	PyTorch Conference
Sep 2023 Energy-Efficient Deep Learning with Zeus	Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Service

• Systems/Software Reading Group, Paper reading group inside Michigan CSE, Organizer since Fall 2022

Teaching _____

- Operating Systems (SNU, Spring 21), Lead TA, Managed Linux kernel hacking projects and led student team design reviews.
- Computer Architecture (SNU, Fall 20), Peer tutor, Provided 30 hours of online lecture, Best Tutor Award!

Language Proficiency _____

ENGLISH

Feb 2020 TOEFL, 120 (full credit) Oct 2018 TOEIC, 900 (full credit) Mar 2018 **GRE**, 167/170/4.5

Skills_____

Language	Python, Rust, CUDA, C++, Verilog, C, Bash
Framework	PyTorch, Pandas, Matplotlib, FastAPI
Methodology	Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Multi-Armed Bandit

Tool Docker, Kubernetes, KubeFlow, LaTeX **English** TOEFL 120 (Perfect score), GRE 167/170/4.5

MARCH 8, 2024 JAE-WON CHUNG